<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>GlenStriders | Premier Running Club in Harare</title><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/feeds/all.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://glenstriders.co.zw/</id><updated>2026-02-25T09:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>From Tired to Transformed: Tracey's Story</title><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/traceys-story.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2026-02-25T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2026-02-25T09:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Glen Striders</name></author><id>tag:glenstriders.co.zw,2026-02-25:/traceys-story.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Women's fitness transformation story: how Tracey went from tired and unconfident to strong and energised by running with Glen Striders club in Harare, Zimbabwe.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glen Striders | Athlete Stories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a moment that many of us know well, standing in front of a mirror, pulling on clothes that don't quite feel right, dragging yourself through the day on empty. For Tracey Mushapaidze, that moment became the turning point that changed everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I wasn't really happy with my body or my energy levels," Tracey shares. "I felt tired most of the time and I wasn't confident. That's when I realized I needed to do something for myself."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last October, Tracey made a decision. She changed her eating habits, laced up her shoes, and started moving. It wasn't her first attempt at getting fit, she'd tried dieting and exercising before, but this time felt different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Before, I wasn't consistent and it frustrated me. It made me feel like I was failing," she admits. "But this time my reason went deeper than just losing weight. I wanted to feel healthy, confident, and comfortable in my own body again. I was tired of feeling low about myself, hiding in clothes, and having no energy. I also wanted to prove to myself that I could stay disciplined."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And prove it she has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center my-4"&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-hero.jpeg" alt="Tracey Mushapaidze running with Glen Striders" class="img-fluid rounded" style="max-width: 800px; width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Small Signs, Big Shifts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first clue that things were really changing came quietly, clothes started fitting differently, and she noticed she had more energy getting through the day. But the transformation wasn't just happening in the mirror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Physically I feel lighter, more energetic, and stronger than before," Tracey says. "Emotionally I feel more confident and proud of myself, even though some days are still hard."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her relationship with food shifted too. Where she once saw food as something to fight against, she now sees it as fuel for her runs, for her health, for her life. "I stopped seeing food as the enemy," she says. "I learned that I am more disciplined and stronger than I ever believed."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row my-4 justify-content-center g-3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-before-image2.jpeg" alt="Tracey before her transformation journey" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-before3.jpeg" alt="Tracey at the start of her fitness journey" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Power of Running Together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest game-changers in Tracey's journey has been running with Glen Striders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What helped me the most was running with a group," she says. "Running with others kept me motivated, pushed me on the hard days, and reminded me that I'm not doing this alone."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center my-4"&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-strory-glen-striders.jpg" alt="Tracey running with the Glen Striders group" class="img-fluid rounded" style="max-width: 800px; width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sense of community became her anchor on the days when giving up felt easier than carrying on. She held onto her &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;  the memory of how she used to feel and let the small wins carry her forward. The encouraging words from people around her who noticed the changes. The runs she finished that she once thought were beyond her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"That's when I understood how strong I had become not just physically, but mentally too. I first felt truly proud of myself when I realized I could finish runs I never thought I would be able to do."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Journey That's Still Going&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracey is clear that she hasn't reached some final destination. She's still working on staying consistent. Some days are still hard. But she carries herself differently now lighter, more confident, more positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"My why changed as I progressed," she reflects. "At first it was about losing weight and feeling better physically. But it became about overall health, confidence, and self-discipline. It wasn't just about the scale anymore. It became about feeling strong and proud of myself."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row my-4 justify-content-center g-3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-finish.jpeg" alt="Tracey at the finish line, celebrating her achievement" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-finish1.jpeg" alt="Tracey celebrating completing a run with Glen Striders" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to anyone standing where she stood a year ago, unsure, tired, wondering if it's even worth trying again  Tracey has one thing to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Start small. Be patient with yourself. And find a supportive group if you can. It really makes the journey easier."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Tracey, for sharing your story with the Glen Striders community. Your courage and honesty remind us all why we run — and why we run together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in joining Glen Striders? &lt;a href="/pages/contact.html"&gt;Reach out to us&lt;/a&gt; and take your first step.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Athlete Stories"/><category term="athlete-stories"/><category term="women-running"/><category term="fitness-transformation"/><category term="running-for-women"/><category term="body-confidence"/><category term="weight-loss"/><category term="running-club-harare"/><category term="motivation"/><category term="community"/><category term="her-miles-harare"/></entry><entry><title>Introducing the Glen Striders Duathlon Series: Running, Community, and Good Times!</title><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/glenstriders-duathlon.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2026-02-08T17:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2026-02-08T17:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Linda</name></author><id>tag:glenstriders.co.zw,2026-02-08:/glenstriders-duathlon.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;At Glen Striders, we believe running isn't just about the kilometers – it's about the connections, the shared journey, and the incredible community we build together.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;At Glen Striders, we believe running isn't just about the kilometers and pounding the pavements – it's about the connections, the shared journey, and the incredible community we build together. That's why we're thrilled to announce a brand-new initiative designed to inject even more fun into our club activities: The Glen Striders Duathlon Series!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center my-4"&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/run-to-pizza.webp" alt="Glen Striders Run to Pizza event - runners enjoying pizza together" class="img-fluid rounded" style="max-width: 800px; width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;What is a Glen Striders Duathlon?&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Duathlon is all about celebrating the joy of running, then seamlessly transitioning into a fun, low-cost social activity. It's our way of extending the camaraderie beyond the final stride, creating memorable experiences and stronger bonds within our running family. Each event will have a unique "Run To..." theme!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We know that after a good run, there's nothing better than unwinding with friends, making new connections, and enjoying great food together. Our aim is to offer these moments without anyone feeling a pinch in their pocket. From post-run pizza gatherings to scenic coffee mornings, we'll be exploring a variety of exciting options.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Kicking Off with "Run To Pizza": Our Slice &amp;amp; Sprint Event!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're incredibly excited to launch our series with everyone's favorite: the "Run To Pizza"! Here's what makes this event special – we'll actually run TO the pizza shop as our destination! Imagine the fun of running together with your fellow Striders, arriving at the pizza shop with the endorphins flowing, enjoying delicious pizza right there, and capturing the moment with great photos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Run Route: We'll run from OK Makomva directly to Pizza Shop – the pizza shop is our destination!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the Pizza Shop: Once we arrive, we'll enjoy pizza together, share stories, and take fun group photos to capture the memories!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Participation Details:&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To keep this event accessible and fun for everyone, we're organizing a great pizza gathering right at the pizza shop!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What to bring: Just bring yourself, your appetite, and maybe your phone or camera for photos! We'll have delicious pizza for everyone to enjoy together at the shop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What the Club provides: We'll organize the pizza and refreshments at the shop location, so all you need to bring is your good cheer, running spirit, and a smile for the photos!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the perfect opportunity to meet new members, catch up with old friends, capture fun memories with photos, and create lasting bonds. Whether you're a seasoned ultra-runner or just starting your running journey, all Glen Striders are welcome!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Keep an eye on our website and social media for announcements about future "Run To..." Duathlon events, including "Run To Coffee," "Run To braai," and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's make our runs even more rewarding. See you on the road and at the pizza party!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Social"/><category term="training"/><category term="social"/></entry><entry><title>Understanding Long Slow Distance (LSD) Runs</title><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/long-slow-distance-runs.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2026-01-18T10:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2026-01-18T10:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Linda</name></author><id>tag:glenstriders.co.zw,2026-01-18:/long-slow-distance-runs.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Learn about the benefits of Long Slow Distance runs and how they can improve your running performance and endurance.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Long Slow Distance (LSD) runs are a cornerstone of endurance training for runners of all levels. Whether you're training for your first 5K or your tenth marathon, incorporating LSD runs into your training routine can significantly improve your running performance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center my-4"&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/lsd-runs-image.jpg" alt="Glen Striders runners on a long slow distance run" class="img-fluid rounded"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;What Are LSD Runs?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LSD runs are exactly what they sound like - long runs performed at a slow, comfortable pace. The emphasis is on building endurance through time on your feet rather than speed. These runs typically last anywhere from 60 minutes to several hours, depending on your fitness level and training goals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;The Benefits of LSD Runs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1. Build Aerobic Base&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;LSD runs improve your cardiovascular system's ability to deliver oxygen to your muscles. This aerobic development is crucial for running longer distances and recovering faster between harder efforts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2. Increase Mitochondrial Density&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Running at a comfortable pace stimulates the growth of mitochondria in your muscle cells. These are the powerhouses that convert oxygen and fuel into energy, making you more efficient as a runner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;3. Strengthen Muscles and Joints&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The extended time on your feet helps strengthen the muscles, tendons, and ligaments used in running. This adaptation reduces injury risk and improves your overall running economy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;4. Mental Toughness&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Long runs teach you to push through fatigue and discomfort, building the mental resilience needed for race day.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;5. Fat Adaptation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At lower intensities, your body learns to use fat as fuel more efficiently, preserving precious glycogen stores for when you need them most.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;How Slow Should You Go?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ideal pace for LSD runs is one where you can maintain a conversation comfortably - often called the "conversational pace." This typically corresponds to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;60-75% of your maximum heart rate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1-2 minutes per kilometer slower than your race pace&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A perceived effort of 5-6 out of 10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don't worry if this feels too slow at first. Remember, the goal is to build endurance, not speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Incorporating LSD Runs at Glen Striders&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At Glen Striders, we embrace LSD runs as part of our Saturday long run sessions. These runs are perfect for:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Runners building up to their first race&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marathon and half-marathon training&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recovery between harder training cycles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social running with club members of all paces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our Saturday long runs provide a supportive environment where you can focus on time on your feet without the pressure of keeping a specific pace. With runners of all levels, you'll always find someone running at your pace.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Tips for Your LSD Runs&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Start conservatively&lt;/strong&gt;: Begin with distances you can comfortably complete&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stay hydrated&lt;/strong&gt;: Carry water or plan routes with water fountains&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fuel properly&lt;/strong&gt;: For runs over 90 minutes, consider taking energy gels or snacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Listen to your body&lt;/strong&gt;: If something hurts, slow down or stop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy the journey&lt;/strong&gt;: Use this time to explore new routes, listen to music, or catch up with fellow runners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Join Us&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every Saturday, Glen Striders meets for our weekly long run. Whether you're running 5K or 35K, there's a group for you. Come experience the benefits of LSD running with our supportive community!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Remember, in running as in life, sometimes the slow and steady approach wins the race. Happy running!&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Training"/><category term="training"/><category term="endurance"/><category term="running-tips"/></entry></feed>