<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>GlenStriders | Premier Running Club in Harare - Athlete Stories</title><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/" rel="alternate"/><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/feeds/athlete-stories.atom.xml" rel="self"/><id>https://glenstriders.co.zw/</id><updated>2026-02-25T09:00:00+02:00</updated><entry><title>From Tired to Transformed: Tracey's Story</title><link href="https://glenstriders.co.zw/traceys-story.html" rel="alternate"/><published>2026-02-25T09:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2026-02-25T09:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>Glen Striders</name></author><id>tag:glenstriders.co.zw,2026-02-25:/traceys-story.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Women's fitness transformation story: how Tracey went from tired and unconfident to strong and energised by running with Glen Striders club in Harare, Zimbabwe.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Glen Striders | Athlete Stories&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There's a moment that many of us know well, standing in front of a mirror, pulling on clothes that don't quite feel right, dragging yourself through the day on empty. For Tracey Mushapaidze, that moment became the turning point that changed everything.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"I wasn't really happy with my body or my energy levels," Tracey shares. "I felt tired most of the time and I wasn't confident. That's when I realized I needed to do something for myself."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Last October, Tracey made a decision. She changed her eating habits, laced up her shoes, and started moving. It wasn't her first attempt at getting fit, she'd tried dieting and exercising before, but this time felt different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Before, I wasn't consistent and it frustrated me. It made me feel like I was failing," she admits. "But this time my reason went deeper than just losing weight. I wanted to feel healthy, confident, and comfortable in my own body again. I was tired of feeling low about myself, hiding in clothes, and having no energy. I also wanted to prove to myself that I could stay disciplined."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And prove it she has.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center my-4"&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-hero.jpeg" alt="Tracey Mushapaidze running with Glen Striders" class="img-fluid rounded" style="max-width: 800px; width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Small Signs, Big Shifts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first clue that things were really changing came quietly, clothes started fitting differently, and she noticed she had more energy getting through the day. But the transformation wasn't just happening in the mirror.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Physically I feel lighter, more energetic, and stronger than before," Tracey says. "Emotionally I feel more confident and proud of myself, even though some days are still hard."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her relationship with food shifted too. Where she once saw food as something to fight against, she now sees it as fuel for her runs, for her health, for her life. "I stopped seeing food as the enemy," she says. "I learned that I am more disciplined and stronger than I ever believed."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row my-4 justify-content-center g-3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-before-image2.jpeg" alt="Tracey before her transformation journey" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-before3.jpeg" alt="Tracey at the start of her fitness journey" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Power of Running Together&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest game-changers in Tracey's journey has been running with Glen Striders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"What helped me the most was running with a group," she says. "Running with others kept me motivated, pushed me on the hard days, and reminded me that I'm not doing this alone."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="text-center my-4"&gt;
  &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-strory-glen-striders.jpg" alt="Tracey running with the Glen Striders group" class="img-fluid rounded" style="max-width: 800px; width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sense of community became her anchor on the days when giving up felt easier than carrying on. She held onto her &lt;em&gt;why&lt;/em&gt;  the memory of how she used to feel and let the small wins carry her forward. The encouraging words from people around her who noticed the changes. The runs she finished that she once thought were beyond her.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"That's when I understood how strong I had become not just physically, but mentally too. I first felt truly proud of myself when I realized I could finish runs I never thought I would be able to do."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;A Journey That's Still Going&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tracey is clear that she hasn't reached some final destination. She's still working on staying consistent. Some days are still hard. But she carries herself differently now lighter, more confident, more positive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"My why changed as I progressed," she reflects. "At first it was about losing weight and feeling better physically. But it became about overall health, confidence, and self-discipline. It wasn't just about the scale anymore. It became about feeling strong and proud of myself."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="row my-4 justify-content-center g-3"&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-finish.jpeg" alt="Tracey at the finish line, celebrating her achievement" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;div class="col-md-6 text-center"&gt;
    &lt;img src="https://glenstriders.co.zw/images/traceys-story-finish1.jpeg" alt="Tracey celebrating completing a run with Glen Striders" class="img-fluid rounded" style="width: 100%; height: auto;"&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And to anyone standing where she stood a year ago, unsure, tired, wondering if it's even worth trying again  Tracey has one thing to say:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;"Start small. Be patient with yourself. And find a supportive group if you can. It really makes the journey easier."&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Thank you, Tracey, for sharing your story with the Glen Striders community. Your courage and honesty remind us all why we run — and why we run together.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interested in joining Glen Striders? &lt;a href="/pages/contact.html"&gt;Reach out to us&lt;/a&gt; and take your first step.&lt;/p&gt;</content><category term="Athlete Stories"/><category term="athlete-stories"/><category term="women-running"/><category term="fitness-transformation"/><category term="running-for-women"/><category term="body-confidence"/><category term="weight-loss"/><category term="running-club-harare"/><category term="motivation"/><category term="community"/><category term="her-miles-harare"/></entry></feed>